# Sufyan Saleem

Address: Phase 6, Sector F8, Street 4, House 425, Hayatabad, Peshawar

Website: https://sufyansaleem.netlify.app/ Email: sufyansalim94@gmail.com Mobile: +923139243550

## **OBJECTIVE**

I am a 24 years old Software Engineer who loves to play with different technologies. I am looking forward for a promising technical job where I will be subjected to new developmental areas with friendly environment for learning and emerging of my own personality with professional and in time work.

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**Decklaration** MERN Stack Engineer Currently Remote Jun 2020 - present Working for NY based design Agency. My main roles include developing Web Applications, Backend and Hybrid Mobile Applications. Linknbit **Software Engineer** Islamabad Pakistan Jan 2019 - May 2020 Working for Software Development and IT Solutions Agency. My main roles include developing Websites, Web Applications and Hybrid Mobile Applications.

#### KYLA APP

Developed the backend in NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, It is a Mobile App to know your laws Node mailer, Geolocation, Recommended actions Security for XSS and NOSQL Contact lawyer with location and Injection details Paid and Unpaid Feature In Development

## Global Aviation System

I am working on parts of backend Node JS, Express, For Central African Republic Swagger, Sequelize cli & Azure In Development SQL

### **Dynasty Unleashed Models**

Modeling agency App for Fashion designers and marketers

Users can register, create profile, add people and hire models at will

### Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native & part of Deployment to Firebase &

Google Play

#### Dokkani.co

- Ecommerce Mobile App.
- User can register, select products, add products to cart.
- User add products to wish list and checkout.

React/React-Native, Expo. Redux, Node JS, Rest API, Word Press API, Woo Commerce API, Native Base

- Project was abandoned on last stage due to funds not provided and outsourced to someone else.
- My Version

#### Yogurt App

 Step-by-step guide to home crafted authentic Yogurt and Kefir. Take the directions on your phone. Make Yogurt and Kefir at home and communicate. Developed part of Front-End in React/React-Native, Expo, Native Base

#### **SmartsAid**

NGO App for refuges

React/React-Native, Expo, Redux, Firebase, Rest API, React Native Elements

2018 - FYP

Currency Recognition & Conversion

 Developed an app where users can scan currency note and it will tell which currency it is and how much is it and show the exchange rate in USD. Android, Java, Open CV, Rest API, MATLAB

2014 - 2018

Content Management Systems

Java, C#, MSSQL

Gym - Point of Sale

PHP, HTML, CSS, MySQL

2010

#### RuneScape RPG

 Created bot script for the game called RuneScape. The bot played the game for you. Java

### **Portfolio Projects**

#### DevCamper API

- Bootcamps API
- One can register as a User or Publisher and login also.
- Publisher can create Bootcamps.
- Admin and Publisher can add courses and perform various CRUD operations.
- Users can comment on Bootcamps and update their profile, add picture, and reset password.

HTML, NodeJS, Express, Mongoose, MongoDB, Node mailer, Security for XSS and NOSQL Injection

#### **DevConnector**

- Social Media for developers where users register.
- Create profile, create posts, add comments and like and unlike them.

React, Redux, CSS, MongoDB, Mongoose, Express, NodeJS, Heroku

#### **SmartBrain**

- Smart Brain an app with face Recognition.
- Users can register, login and submit images via URL.
- The AI recognizes the face in the picture and draw a border around.

React, Redux, CSS, PostgreSQL, Knex, Express, Nodejs, Heroku, Netlify It works only for one face in the image.

#### The Color App

React, JSS, Material UI,

- A cross between flatuicolors and materialuicolors.
- Users can copy colors from palettes and create new color palettes, can also make colors lighter and darker by using the slider.
- When creating palettes one can also drag colors around and sort them however they like.

## **EDUCATION**

### Internet of things and AI Specialist Course

PIAIC, Islamabad (2019 - present)

### BS in Software Engineering, cgpa 2.78

Institute of Managements Sciences, Peshawar (2014 – 2018)

## F.Sc - Pre-Engineering, grade B

ICMS College System Peshawar (2012 – 2014)

## 10 Matric, grade A

Racines School System, Peshawar (2010 – 2012)

## **SPECIALITY AND KNOWLEDGE**

**LANGUAGES AND HOBBIES** 

## **Specialities**

Mobile/Hybrid App Developer Web Developer

#### **Social Links**









## Knowledge

React/React-Native, Redux, Expo JS, Node JS, Express Mongoose, Sequelize Firebase, Mongo DB HTML, CSS, JSS, Bootstrap Git, Heroku, Netlify Rest, GraphQL, MVC Rust

## Word press, Android Studio, Adobe PS

### Languages

English Urdu Pashto

### **Hobbies**

Programming, Music, Movies, Video Games, Reading, Hiking, Bodybuilding,